Hello everyone and welcome to this lesson on deep learning with PyTorch.
大家好！欢迎学习“深度学习工具 PyTorch”课程
So, in this lesson I'm going to be showing you how we can
在这节课 我将演示
build neural networks with pyTorch and train them.
如何使用 PyTorch 构建神经网络并训练网络
By working through all these notebooks I built,
在 notebook 里学习并练习完之后
you'll be writing the actual code yourself for building these networks.
你将自己编写代码来构建网络
By the end of the lesson,
这节课的目标是
you will have built your own state of the art image classifier.
构建一个图像分类器
But first we're going to start with basics,
但首先我们会学习基础知识
so how do you build just a simple neural network in pyTorch?
那么 如何在 PyTorch 中构建一个简单的神经网络？
So, as a reminder of how neural networks work,
回顾下神经网络的工作原理
in general we have some input values so here x1,
这里有一些输入值 例如 x1 x2
x2, and we multiply them by some weights w and bias.
我们用它们乘以权重 w 和偏差
So, this b is this bias we just multiply it by one then you sum all these up
这个 b 表示偏差 我们乘以 1
and you get some value h. Then we have what's called an activation function.
将这几个值相加得出 h 然后是激活函数
So, here f of h and passing
即这里的 f(h)
these input values h through this activation function gets you output y.
将这些输入值之和 h 传入激活函数 得出输出 y
This is the basis of neural networks.
这就是神经网络的基本原理
You have these inputs,
这些是输入
you multiply it by some waves, take the sum,
乘以某些权重
pass it through some activation function and you get an output.
传入激活函数 得出输出
You can stack these up so that the output of these units,
你可以继续堆叠这个结构
of these neurons go to another layer like another set of weights.
将这些单元（神经元）的输出传入采用另一组权重的另一个层级
So, mathematically this what it looks like, y,
数学公式是这样的
our output is equal to this linear combination of the weights and
输出 y 等于权重 w 和输入值 x
the input values w's and x's plus your bias value
及偏差值 b 的线性组合
b passes through your activation function f and you get y.
然后放入激活函数 f 里并得出 y
You could also write it with this sum.
也可以写成这样的求和公式
So, sum of wi times xi and plus b, your bias term.
w^i 乘以 x^i 的和加上偏差项 b
That gives you y.
得出 y
So, what's nice about this is that you can actually think of the x's,
这个公式的好处是
your input features, your values,
可以将输入特征（值）x 当做向量
as a vector, and your weights as another vector.
并将权重当做另一个向量
So, your multiplication and sum is the same as a dot or inner product of two vectors.
因此这里的相乘求和与两个向量的点积/内积是相同的
So, if you consider your input as a vector and your weights as a vector,
如果将输入和权重当做向量
if you take the dot product of these two,
可以对这两个向量求点积
then you get your value h and then you pass
然后得出值 h
h through your activation function and that gets you your output y.
并将 h 传入激活函数里 得出输出 y
So, now if we start thinking of our weights and our input values as vectors,
现在我们将权重和输入值当做向量
so vectors are an instance of a tensor.
向量是一种张量
So, a tensor is just a generalization of vectors and matrices.
张量是向量和矩阵的泛化形式
So, when you have these like regular structured arrangements of
这些是普通的数据结构
values and so a tensor with only one dimension is a vector.
一维张量是向量
So, we just have this single one-dimensional array of values.
这是一个一维值数组
So, in this case characters T-E-N-S-O-R. A matrix like this is
这里是字符 ‘t’ ‘e’ ‘n’ ‘s’ ‘o’ ‘r’
a two-dimensional tensor and so we have values going in
像这样的矩阵是二维张量
two directions from left to right and from top to
这些值按从左到右和从上到下这两个方向排列
bottom and so that we have individual rows and columns.
它们分别是行和列
So, you can do operations across the columns like
你可以沿着一行对列执行操作
along a row or you can do it across the rows like going down a column.
或沿着一列对行执行操作
You also have three-dimensional tensors so you can think of
这个是三维张量
an image like an RGB color image as a three-dimensional tensor.
可以看做三维的 RGB 彩色图像
So, for every pixel,
对于每个像素
there's some value for all the red and the green
所有的红绿蓝通道
and the blue channels and so for every individual pixel,
都有某个值
in a two-dimensional image,
因此在二维图像中
you have three values.
每个像素都有三个值
So, that is a three-dimensional tensor.
这就是三维张量
Like I said before, tensors are a generalization of
正如我刚刚提到的 张量是一种泛化形式
this so you can actually have four-dimensional,
因此可以有四维
five-dimensional, six-dimensional, and so on like tensors.
五维 六维张量等等
It's just the ones that we normally work with are
但是我们通常处理的是
one and two-dimensional, three-dimensional tensors.
一维 二维和三维张量
So, these tensors are the base data structure that you use
这些张量是
an pyTorch and other neural network frameworks.
pyTorch 和其他神经网络框架中的基本数据结构
So, TensorFlow is named after tensors.
TensorFlow 就是根据张量命名的
So, these are the base data structures that
这些就是你要使用的基本数据结构
you'll be using so you pretty much need to understand
你必须熟练掌握它们
them really well to be able to use
才能够使用
pretty much any framework that you'll be using for deep learning.
深度学习框架
So, let's get started. I'm going to show you how to actually create
我们开始吧我将演示如何创建张量
some tensors and use them to build a simple neural network.
并使用它们构建简单的神经网络
So, first we're going to import pyTorch and so just import torch here.
首先 我们将导入 PyTorch 在这里输入 import torch
Here I am creating activation function,
我在这里创建了激活函数
so this is the Sigmoid activation function.
这是 S 型激活函数
It's the nice s shape that kind of squeezes the input values between zero and one.
它是一个完美的 S 型图形 将输入值压缩到了 0 和 1 之间
It's really useful for providing a probability.
非常适合提供概率值
So, probabilities are these values that can only be between zero and one.
概率值只能位于 0 到 1 之间
So, you're Sigmoid activation if you want
因此 如果你希望
the output of your neural network to be a probability,
神经网络的输出为概率
then the sigmoid activation is what you want to use.
则建议使用 S 型激活函数
So, here I'm going to create some fake data, I'm generating some data,
我将创建一些虚拟数据 生成一些权重和偏差
I'm generating some weights and biases and with these you're actually going to
你将使用这些虚拟值进行计算
do the computations to get the output of a simple neural network.
并获得简单神经网络的输出
So, here I'm just creating a manual seeds.
在这里创建 manual_seed()
So, I'm setting the seed for the random number generation that I'll
设置将要使用的随机数
be using and here I'm creating features.
在这里创建特征
So, features are like the input features of the input data for your network.
特征是指网络的输入特征/输入数据
Here we see torch.randn.
这里是 torch.randn()
So, randn is going to create a tensor of normal variables.
randn 将创建由正态变量组成的张量
So, random normal variables as samples from a normal distribution.
即来自正态分布的随机正态变量
You give it a tuple of the size that you want.
指定元组大小
So, in this case I want the features to be a matrix,
这里我希望特征是一个矩阵
a 2-dimensional tensor of one row and five columns.
即包含 1 行和 5 列的二维张量
So, you can think of this as a row vector that has five elements.
可以将它看做有 5 个元素的行向量
For the weights, we're going to create another matrix
对于矩阵 我们将创建另一个矩阵
of random normal variables and this time I'm using randn_like.
并使用随机正态变量 这次我将使用 randn_like
So, what this does is it takes
它的原理是
another tensor and it looks at the shape of this tensor and then it creates it,
传入一个张量并查看该张量的形状
it creates another tensor with the same shape.
然后创建形状相同的另一个张量
So, that's what this this like means.
这就是这个“like”的含义
So, I'm going to create a tensor of
我将使用随机正态变量创建一个张量
random normal variables with the same shape as features. So, it gives me my weights.
形状和 features 张量的一样这就是权重
Then I'm going to create a bias term.
然后我将创建偏差项
So, this is again just a random normal variable.
还是随机正态变量
Now I'm just creating one value.
现在我只创建一个值
So, this is one row and one column.
这是 1 行和 1 列
Here I'm going to leave this exercise up to you.
现在布置一道练习题
So, what you're going to be doing is taking the features, weights,
你需要根据特征 权重
and the bias tensors and you're going to
和偏差张量
calculate the output of this simple neural network.
计算这个简单神经网络的输出
So, remember with features and weights you want to take
注意 你需要对特征和权重求内积
the inner product or you want to multiply the features by
即将特征和权重相乘并求和
the weights and sum them up and then add the bias and then pass it through
然后加上偏差项
the activation function and from that you should get the output of your network.
最后传入激活函数 得出网络的输出
So, if you want to see how I did this,
如果你想查看我是如何实现的
checkout my solution notebook or watch
请参阅我的 solution notebook
the next video which I'll show you my solution for this exercise.
或者观看下个视频 我会讲解这道练习的答案